Hello, and welcome to Problem Session 9
大家好 这是习题课 9
of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
配套于 Wolfram U 微积分入门
The topic for this session is numerical approximation of integrals,
本节的主题是关于积分的数值近似
average value of a function, exponentials and logarithms.
函数的均值 以及指数和对数
Let’s begin with the first problem on the session.
来从第一个问题开始
The first problem says compute the derivative of 2e^x.
问题 1 计算 2e^x 的导数
Now the derivative of e^x is itself,
看 e^x 的导数就是他自己
so the required derivative is 2e^x.
因此需要的导数是 2e^x
Let’s confirm that with D.
我们用 D 确认一下
Here is a plot of the derivative.
这是导数的图像
On to number 2, which says compute the indefinite integral of 3^x.
问题 2 计算 3^x 的不定积分
The answer is simply 3^x/Log[3].
很简单答案是 3^x/Log[3]
Let’s check that with Integrate.
用 Integrate 核实一下
That’s correct.
是对的
Let’s plot both the function and integral, and of course
画出函数图像 当然
they just differ by a scale factor of Log[3].
他和 Log[3] 就差乘一个常数
On to number 3, which says compute the derivative of 2^x^2.
问题 3 计算 2^x^2 的导数
Now that’s a bit harder and requires the chain rule.
现在有点难了 要用链式法则
You work out the as 2^x^2Log[2] times the derivative of x^2,
用 2^x^2Log[2] 乘 x^2 的导数
which is 2x.
他是 2x
You can check that with D.
可以用 D 检查
Notice there’s a 2^(1 + x^2) over here.
注意到这的 2^(1 + x^2)、
That’s where the extra 2 goes.
这里就是多了 2 的地方
Let’s plot the function and the derivative.
画函数的图像和导数的图像
You can see over here that the 2 occurs right over here.
你可以看到 2 就在这里发生
Okay. On to number 4, which says
好 问题 4
compute the integral from 0 to π/2 of Cos[x]e^Sin[x].
计算从 0 到 π/2 的积分 Cos[x]e^Sin[x]
You make a small substitution.
做个代换
You let u = Sin[x].
令 Sin[x] = u
The du = Cos[x]dx, the derivative of Sin[x].
那么 du = Cos[x]dx 就是 Sin[x] 的导数
Then you get a very simple integral
然后得到一个非常简单的积分
because the limits become 0 to 1 when x is 0.
因为当 x 是 0 的时候上下限变为 0
Then Sin[x] is 0.
Sin[x] 是 0
When x is π/2, Sin[x] is 1, so you get e^u from 0 to 1,
当 x 是 π/2 时 Sin[x] 是 1 所以有 e^u 从 0 到 1
which is—Integrate gives you e – 1.
他的积分 Integrate 算的是 e – 1
Let’s check the answer with Integrate,
用 Integrate 检查一下
and you get back the same answer.
得到相同的答案
Now let’s plot the region being integrated,
绘制被积区域的图像
and that’s the required plot.
这是我们的图
On to number 5, which says compute the derivative of 4Log[3x].
问题 5 计算 4Log[3x] 的导数
The answer is going to be 4 times the derivative of Log[3x],
答案是 Log[3x] 的导数的 4 倍
which will be 1/3x, times 3 by the chain rule, so the answer is 4/x.
他是 1/3x 通过链式法则乘 3 所以答案是 4/x
Let’s confirm that with D, and you do get back 4/x.
用 D 验证 得到 4/x
Here is a plot of the function and its derivative.
这是函数和他的导数的图像
On to number 6, which says compute the integral
问题 6 计算积分
of x/(x^2 + 2) from –1 to 3.
x/(x^2 + 2) 在 -1 到 3 之间
Make a small substitution.
用一个小替换
Let u be x^2 + 2, so du is 2xdx, the derivative of x^2 + 2.
让 u 是 x^2 + 2 所以 du 是 2xdx 是 x^2 + 2 的导数
Now when x is –1, then u is 3.
当 x 是 -1 时 u 是 3
When x is 3, then 3^2 + 2 is 11, so u is 11.
当 x 是 3 时 3^2 + 2 是 11 所以 u is 11
You get back a much simpler integral which requires the Log function
得到一个更简单的积分 他需要用 Log 函数
and the answer is 1/2Log[11/3].
答案是 1/2Log[11/3]
Let’s check with Integrate, and you do get back the same answer.
用 Integrate 检查 得到相同的答案
Here is a plot of the region that we just integrated.
这是我们刚刚积分的区域图像
On to number 7, which says find
问题 7 计算
the derivative of Log[x] to the base 5.
以 5 为底 Log[x] 的导数
Well, that’s just going to be 1/xLog[5]
好吧 他就是 1/xLog[5]
because you can rewrite the input as Log[x]/Log[5].
因为你可以将输入改写为 Log[x]/Log[5]
Let’s check the answer with D,
用 D 检查答案
and here is a plot of the function and its derivative.
这是函数和他的导数的图像
On to number 8, which says compute the indefinite integral of Log[2x].
问题 8 计算不定积分 Log[2x]
Well, we need a small substitution.
做一个小替换
Let u be 2x, so du is 2dx.
让 u 是 2x 所以 du 是 2dx
Then you get the integral of Log[u]du/2.
然后得到积分 Log[u]du/2
Remember that the integral of Log[u] is uLog[u] – u,
记住 Log[u] 的积分是 uLog[u] – u
so the answer is xLog[2x] – x + C.
所以答案是 xLog[2x] – x + C
Here’s the same answer from Integrate minus the constant C,
这是  Integrate 的答案减了  C
and here is a plot of the function and its integral when C is 0.
这是 C 是 0 的时候的函数及其积分的图
On to number 9, which says compute the average value
问题 9 计算均值
of the cubed root of x from 1 to 27.
x 的立方根 从 1 到 27
Now the average value formula is
现在的均值公式里
1 over the upper limit minus the lower limit—
上限 27 减去下限
that’s the length of the interval—
这是区间长度
times the integral of the function over that integral.
乘函数在区域上的积分
Compute with Integrate and you get back 30/13,
用 Integrate 得 30/13
and here is a plot of the function
这是函数图像
and its average value on the same integral.
这是他在同一个区域上的均值
On to number 10, which says find the point at which
问题 10 找到这一点
the average value of this function over a certain interval
函数在确定区域内的均值
equals the function value.
等于这个函数值
Now that equals suggests that
现在等于表明
you want to apply the mean value theorem.
你应用均值定理
Let’s do that.
来做
We solve the equation function value at a point c
我们解方程 函数在 c 处的值
equal to the main value, and you get back that c is about 0.785.
等于均值 你得到 c 大概是 0.785
Here is a plot of the function and its average value.
这是函数及其均值的图
On to number 11, which says compute the average value of e^(x/2)
问题 11 计算 e^(x/2) 的均值
over the interval 3 to 5.
在 3 到 5 之间
That’s just a computation.
这只是一个计算
It’s 1/(5 – 3) times the integral of the function over the interval.
1/(5 – 3) 乘函数在区间上的积分
Here is the average value.
这是均值
Then finally we have a plot of the function and the average value.
最后我们画函数和他均值的图像
On to number 12,  which says use the midpoint rule
问题 12 用中点法
with eight rectangles to compute the numerical approximation
以 8 个矩形做数值近似
for this integral over here.
对这个积分
For the midpoint rule, you take the midpoints
对于中点法 取中点
as the points of the rectangles touch the curve,
是矩形和曲线接触的点
so the width of each rectangle of course is just π/24
当然每个矩形的宽是 π/24
because you have eight rectangles, and you want the sample points
因为你有 8 个矩形 然后采样点
to be the midpoints of each subinterval.
就是每个子区间的中点
The sum is going to be the sum from 1 to 8
求和是从 1 加到 8
of the width of each rectangle
没个矩形的宽
times the value of the function at the midpoint.
乘重点处的函数值
Compute it with Sum.
计算和式
You get back 0.7895 approximately.
得到近似值是 0.7895
Check with NIntegrate, the built-in numerical integrator,
用 NIntegrate 验算 这个内置数值积分器
and your values agree quite nicely because
和你算的非常一致 因为
the midpoint rule is quite a powerful rule for approximation.
中点法是非常强大的近似方法
On to number 13, which says use the trapezoidal rule
问题 13 用梯形法
to estimate the integral over here.
近似这个积分
Now for the trapezoidal rule, of course you’ll take the height to be
对于梯形法 当然将高设为
just the width of these subintervals.
子区间的宽度
That’s (2π – e)/5 because you want five trapezoids.
是 (2π – e)/5 因为你想用 5 个梯形
Then you multiply that by the average, so to speak,
然后将其乘以均值 可以说
of the values at the two endpoints,
两个端点的均值
and you get back the approximation.
然后你得到这个近似
In this case, the approximation is not very good
这里 这个近似不是非常好
because the trapezoidal rule is typically not very accurate.
因为梯形法通常不是非常精确
On to number 14.
问题 14
How about Simpson’s rule?
辛普森法如何？
You want to apply Simpson’s rule with 10 subsections
用 10 个子区间的辛普森法
to compute the integral of Sin[Sin[x]] from 0 to π/2.
计算积分 Sin[Sin[x]] 从 0 到 π/2
That’s a very difficult integral,
这是个非常复杂的积分
but Simpson’s rule works really well over here.
但是辛普森法的效果很好
The first step is you break up the integral into 10 subsections
第一步是将区间划分为 10 个子区间
and you get π/20 for each of them as the length.
每个区间长度是  π/20
Then apply the rule, which is basically you want to use
应用方法 基本上你用
the rule 1, 4, 1—the values at f[2i – 2], f[2i – 1] and f[2i].
这个方法 1 4 1 在 f[2i – 2] f[2i – 1] 和 f[2i] 处的函数值
Compute the approximation from Simpson’s rule,
根据辛普森法计算近似值
and it agrees quite well with the actual answer.
他和实际答案吻合的很好
That brings me to the end of this problem session.
本节课到此为止
I hope you have learned a lot about average values
我希望大家都能足够了解函数的均值
and approximations and exponentials and logs by now.
近似值 还有指数和对数
I’ll stop over here. Thank you very much.
下课 再见
翻译：兰州大学 周怀尚